Guide to the American Life Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory
  - Religious literature: Protestant Episcopal Book Society. One resting place. Philadelphia, The Society, n.d. 7 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Financial documents
    - Eagle Fire Company of New York: Two fire insurance policies issued to Dyer White for a house on Orange Street, New Haven. 1806, 1808. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Pomroy, Joseph H., carriage manufacturer: Bill to "Mr. Walton," April 9, 1870. New York (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Festivals: Fairbanks Post No. 17, Department of Michigan, G.A.R.. Memorial Day. Record of its observance...with addresses of Gen. L.S. Trowbridge and Rev. E.L. Rexford. Detroit, W.S. Ostler's Power Presses, 1882. 32 p. With signature on title page: L.S.T. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Campaign literature
    - 16 items of pro-Hoover literature from the presidential campaign of 1928. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - 1 envelope stamped, "Nixon in '64" sent in 1961. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Adams, Francis M, collector
    - University of Cambridge, Massachusetts: Order of excercises for commencement... Cambridge, University Press, 1818. 4 p. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Prosody. [n.p., 1835] 2 p. on one leaf. The rules of prosody in Latin and Greek. Francis M. Adams, Feb 12, 1835 written in ink on the first page. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - ...Appendix. Terminations of Substantives... [n.p., 1835]. 8 p. Latin declensions. Francis M. Adams, 183? printed across the top. Page torn. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Valentine in cut-work paper, with the initials F.M.A. and the date, 1825, in ink. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Printed form from Charleston College. 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Emblem of the Magnolia Division No. 119 S. of T., Gloucester, Mass. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Advertisement: "Oratory and music in the Church St. church..." New Haven, Conn., Palladium Office Print., 1840 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Infants - Care and hygiene
    - How to keep the baby well. New York, Department of Health, 1911. 36 x 20 cm. illus. Instructions on the recto. List of Infants' milk stations in Manhattan on verso.[Placard] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Regole d'Igiene per la salute dei bambini. Boston, Lega per la coltivazione della salute, [ca.1909-1912]. [Placard 35x25 cm.] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - International Grenfell Association: 57 TLS by Alberta Morbio Pruett written to her mother, Rosa Sutro Morbio and other members of her family while working as a nurse with the Grenfell expedition in Lewis Bay, Labrador. 1924 Jun 1-1925 Jun 21. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Theater programs: The last visit to America. Sarah Bernhardt. Season 1910-1911. Joan of Arc as represented by Mme. Sarah Bernhardt and company. Under the Direction of Wm. F. Connor. New York, F. Rullman, [1910]. 23p. Autographed: Sarah Bernhardt. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Railroads
    - New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad. Timetable. New York ...New Haven. New Canaan Branch. October 14, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - N.Y. Central and Hudson River Railroad. Ticket stub for a trip from Little Falls to Amsterdam. Oct 13, 1882. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Boston: United States Hotel. Boston. Engraving.[ca. 1890?]. 9x14 cm. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Humor: Miscellaneous newspaper clippings with jokes, humorous anecdotes, etc. 1883. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Newspapers: Washington, D.C. Daily Evening Star. Receipt for a three months subscription. (Printed form filled in.) November 25, 1854. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Politics and government
    - Cleveland, Grover, Pres. U.S., 1837-1903/Campaign pin in gilt metal with the photograph of Cleveland set in. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Election campaign, 1948 - Republican Party/Campaign buttons for Dewey and Warren. 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Travel brochures: This week in Indianapolis. Indianapolis, Convention and publicity Bureau, October 1933. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - U.S. United States Savings Bonds Division
    - A portfolio containing samples of booklets used in the division's direct mail campaign to promote the sale of United States Savings Bonds., 1935-1941 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Beach, Adilie
    - Autograph album with verses and sentiments inscribed to Adilie Beach. 1879 Apr, May, Mansfield, Pa.; 1916 Aug 6, Orlando, Fla. 1 v. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Women: A collection of pamphlet and leaflets issued by the Woman's Industrial Exhibition, 1912; National American Woman Suffrage Association, the Women's Trade Union League the Bell Telephone Company (on its women operators) and miscellaneous items relating to women. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Recipes: A collection of manuscript recipes, with two newspaper clippings., Circa 1863 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Peary, Robert Edwin, 1856-1920
    - Menu of the Annual Dinner of the Explorer's Club, Hotel Astor, New York. Autographed by Robert E. Peary on the verso., 1909 December 10. (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Advertisements - Travel: Brochures, leaflets, postcards relating to trans-Atlantic travel, 1927-1940. (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Railroads: Card with photographs of trains and stations of the Mohawk & Hudson River Railroad. 1916, New Haven (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Education: Ms lesson book with exercises in penmanship, geometry and French. Included also are three pages of accounts in English and French kept by a jeweler, 1858. (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Commonplace books: Two commonplace books with excerpts of poetry and prose. One with a genealogy of the Benedict family., 1869, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Public health: Chicago. Dept. of Health. Quarantine notice for diptheria., [ca.1912]. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Consumers' League of the City of New York. Brochure on its Christmas shopping policy., undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Advertisements
    - The Witchraft Advertiser. v.19, no.77 (January 1901). A complete magazine in which every item has a mention of Sapolio. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Advertisements for various services and products in the form of leaflets, brochers and cards. Included also are two trade cards. 14 items, Circa1914 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Education - 19th century
    - Lists of spelling exercises. Embossed on Paper. (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - A composition on the Fourth of July pricked on paper. (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Newport, Rhode Island
    - Brochure for the sale of property in Newport, with photographs of the city and environs., With newspaper clippings on the sale., 1920 August (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Artifacts
    - Cardboard pillbox from E. Hewitt & Co. Pharmacits of New Haven. (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Folding waxed paper drinking cup. (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Public health: Louisiana. State Board of Health/ Poster. "Typhoid fever can be prevented..." 1915. 48x32 cm. (Box 4)
  - Phrenology: Fowler, O.S. & L.N./ Phrenological chart. Presenting a synopsis of the science, and designed to accompany "Phronology proved, illustrated and applied;" by O.S. & L.N. Fowler, assisted by S. Kirkham. 60x49 cm. (Box 4)
  - Inspirational literature
    Message No. 1, Good Cheer
    Message No. 2, Be Not Afraid
    - The Trotty Veck Messengers. Saranac, N.Y. (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Pamphlet entitled "The Old Family Coach: An American Game for a Large Party of Children", [1864] (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Poetry: "Housekeeper's Rubaiyat," by Olive Green [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Fraternal organizations
    - Two advertising palm cards, two admission tickets, and a Red Hand of Ulster ribbon and badge for the Pittsburgh Irish Protestant fraternal organization's balls and banquets., 1874, 1877, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 54)